Jett T. Kendrick

Chicago, IL • <u>jettkendrick@gmail.com</u> • 312-480-1059 Github.com/jettkendrick • linkedin.com/in/jett-kendrick • jettkendrick.github.io

Full Stack Software Developer

Web developer with a background in software and hardware. Experienced in managing large projects as a network administrator for multi-unit retail business with hundreds of employees. Strong analytical and creative mindset focusing on continued learning and writing clean code.

Technical Skills: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Vue.JS, HTML, CSS, SQL, Postgres, APIs, and Git

Experience

Actualize, Web Developer

September 2018 – Present

- **Bootcamp**: Completed the intensive, 3-month Actualize bootcamp and learned Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Vue.JS. Learned how to think as a software engineer and gained the ability to tackle any new technology.
- **Stelt:** Personally created a style-focused app centered around styles of celebrities and their outfits and emulating their look without breaking the bank. Pictures of a celebrities and their outfits are uploaded alongside pictures of products that look similar to each individual item in the outfit. Each picture is linked to a site where the similar-looking product can be purchased at an affordable price. It was built using a Ruby on Rails backend with a Vue.js frontend and implemented with the Tumblr-API to scrape data.

Buchanan Energy

IT Specialist 2016 – Present

- Executed the Responsibilities of the IT Department, including troubleshooting technological issues involving Chicago corporate office and 100+ company stores in Greater Chicago Area, St. Louis, and Houston.
- Maintained the network of each store so that necessary hardware and programs function properly.
- Led IT Tech Committee and collaborated with Omaha Branch in company-wide project implementing proprietary cloud service for 700+ employees and provided training for employees.
- Built evaluation forms used by auditors and marketing department

Fuel Dispatcher

2012 - 2016

- Responsible for dispatching 400K gallons a day in fuel for large petroleum company
- Created dispatch software to improve dispatching times and increased profits to the bottom line of the company.

Deuces and the Diamond Club

2013 - 2016

Barback

- Provided quality customer service in a fast pace environment
- Was flexible in work hours sometimes working 18 hour shifts to get the job done.

Education

Columbia College Chicago

2012 - 2015

Coursework in Creative Writing and General Education